SHARADA JAYAWEERA

DEVOPS ENGINEER

+358 417235222

PROFILE

sharada.prabash@gmail.com



Orivedenkatu 8F 113, 33720 Tampere

www.linkedin.com/in/ in sharada-jayaweera



https:// sharadajay.github.io/

DevOps Engineer, with experience Software in Development with Java, Spring Boot, Angular, Python, Go (Golang), Cloud Services, CI/CD toolchain and Identity and Access Management (IAM). Known for excellent problem solving skills and creative solutions to solve complex challenges. A forward-thinking professional, always pushing the boundaries of technology to deliver impactful results.

EXPERIENCES

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Aug. 2023 - Nov. 2023

Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd. I Sri Lanka

- Managed and maintained a customized IAM solution built on top of WSO2 Identity Server with Single Sign-On (SSO) functionality.
- Worked as a full-stack developer for ADL Axonect Enterprise Enabler platform team. (https://axonect.com/axonect-enterprise-enabler/)

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd. I Sri Lanka

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2023

- Worked as a full-stack developer for ADL Axonect Enterprise Enabler platform team.
- Worked as a L3 Support Engineer managing GCP Cloud Infrastructure, CI/CD tools, Software Deployments and Application Monitoring (Dynatrace, Cloud dashboards).
- Worked as an Research Engineer to develop a Network Management and Orchestration Tool for modern networks (4G/5G) leveraging ONAP, OSM and FREE5GC.
- Designed and developed a fully event-driven system using AWS Lambda functions, S3, EventBridge, CloudWatch, SNS, KMS and IAM. Created CloudFormation templates

R&D ENGINEERING INTERN

Jun. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Centre for Smart Systems (CS2), Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD) I Singapore

• Developed devices for Air Quality monitoring, designed enclosures using SOLIDWORKS and developed Mobile Applications using Android Studio and Flutter for the configuration and data visualization of the devices.



EDUCATION

Tampere University, Finland

2023 - Present | M.Sc. (Tech) in Computing Sciences and Electrical Engineering

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

2016 - 2021 | B.Sc. Eng. Hons. in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

- CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator - The Linux Foundation
- **CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer** - The Linux Foundation

SKILLS

Programming & Scripting Languages

- Java
- Go (Golang)
- Python
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Bash

Frameworks & Libraries

- Spring Boot
- Angular
- Gin
- React
- Django

Cloud Services

- AWS
- GCP
- OpenStack
- Azure

Container Technologies

- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Helm

CI/CD & Version Control Tools

- Git
- Jenkins
- GitLab
- GitHub

DevOps & Project Management

- Terraform
- Linux
- Ansible
- RabbitMQ
- Nexus
- Atlassian Stack (Jira, Confluence)

Databases

- MvSQL
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Redis

APIs

- REST
- GraphQL